Hello.
So here we will be talking about physical characteristics.
So the physical properties of proximity integrated circuit cards pics specified in part one of the ISO
14,143, essentially correspond to the requirements specified for smart cards with contacts.
The dimensions match the dimensions of ID one card specified in ISO 7810.
This ensures that the card will fit in terminals designed for magnetic stripes, cards, or contact
cards.
It must be expected that in normal use, proximity cards will be exposed to electromagnetic fields corresponding
to those intended for use with other types of cards, such as cards that comply with the ISO ten, 50,
136 or ISO 15,693 standards.
The cards must not suffer permanent damage as the result of exposure to these fields, or the effects
of exposure to normal ambient electromagnetic fields.
In order to ensure this, the standard specifies the maximum strengths of alternating electric and magnetic
fields that the cards must withstand without damage.
It's the responsibility of the semiconductor manufacturer to design chips that meet these requirements.
So first think about physical characteristics is the antenna classes.
So as you can see here the class one for PCC correspond to ID one type ID one dimensions.
So and as you can see here in these six pictures, when we go higher in the type of the class, we go
lower on the dimensions of the cards.
For example, the class one is the biggest type of cards in term of dimensions, and the class six is
the smallest one in term of dimensions.
The second thing about physical characteristics is the AMF, the alternating magnetic field.
In fact, this is one of the tests that we need to do on a card in order to make sure that it doesn't
burn or it doesn't broke.
After exposing it in a very high value of the field generated by the reader, for example.
In fact, when, for example, your card is just next to a reader that is generated a very high value
of the field, the card should not broke or should not be damaged after this exposure.
So this is the AMF test is one of the tests that we need to do on a card.
For example.
We need to.
In fact, it consists on exposing the card in a 10 ampere/m field generated by the reader for five minutes.
And then once we finish this test, we need to to send some comments to the card in order to see if
it's still alive, if it's still working.